<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://localhost:4000/assets/xslt/rss.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://localhost:4000/assets/css/rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>KN - Portfolio</title>
		<description>» A portfolio / blog «</description>
		<link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
		<atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>The Nuclear Ensemble Approach</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/blog/nuclear-ensemble-approach</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/nuclear-ensemble-approach</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>AtmoSpec: A Revolutionary Tool for Atmospheric Chemists</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/blog/what-is-atmospec</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In the realm of atmospheric chemistry, &lt;strong&gt;Volatile Organic Compounds (VOCs)&lt;/strong&gt; are extremely important, as they can significantly influence air quality and climate, yet their photochemical reactivities and lifetimes are often poorly understood. This lack of knowledge is primarily due to the challenges associated with isolating and measuring these transient VOCs, which stands in the way of conventional laboratory methods. 
Understanding how VOCs interact with sunlight is essential for developing accurate atmospheric chemistry models. &lt;strong&gt;Photoabsorption cross-sections&lt;/strong&gt; are key parameters that describe how much light a molecule can absorb at different wavelengths. This information is crucial for predicting the photolysis processes that VOCs undergo, which in turn affects their reactivity and lifetime in the atmosphere. Unfortunately, obtaining these cross-sections experimentally can be difficult, often unfeasable due to their instability. Recent advances in computational photochemistry allow for the calculation of these photoabsorption cross-sections, but this can be inaccessible to those less computationally savvy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;atmospec-an-automated-workflow-using-nea&quot;&gt;AtmoSpec: An Automated Workflow Using NEA&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address these challenges, the InSilico Photochemistry group at the University of Bristol have developed an interactive computational tool, AtmoSpec, that automates the calculation of photoabsorption cross-sections for VOCs using the &lt;strong&gt;Nuclear Ensemble Approach (NEA)&lt;/strong&gt;. This automated workflow simplifies the process, allowing users to input a molecule’s structure via a simple SMILES code and select a theoretical framework. AtmoSpec then performs the necessary quantum chemistry calculations using ORCA, and provides users with the photoabsorption cross-section for the molecule’s low-energy conformers, along with estimates of photolysis rate coefficients for various actinic fluxes. This abstraction of a complex computational process makes advances in computational chemistry accessible to researchers less familiar with such methods, giving them access to quantum mechanical tools in their respective areas of research&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AtmoSpec is built on the Aiidalab ecosystem, with an integrated database and workflow manager for seamless execution of calculations and storage of results. Moreover, Quantum Chemistry calculations can be configured for local execution or on the cloud, allowing for greater flexibility. Similarly, the web application delivery allows for remote access from anywhere in the world, and the containerization via Docker ensures robust deployment in any environment. The open source nature encourages contributions and collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;future-improvements&quot;&gt;Future Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, the InSilicoPhotochemistry group are committed to continuous improvement of the tool. Future enhancements will focus on implementing a improvements in the Nuclear Ensemble Approach, such as &lt;a href=&quot;/portfolio/rep-sampling-for-nea/&quot; title=&quot;Learn about representative sampling techniques&quot;&gt;Representative Sampling Techniques&lt;/a&gt; to improve the efficiency of the algorithm, thereby making it more applicable to larger, more complex molecules. Additionally, interfacing the application with the GPU accellerated package TeraChem will provide appreciable speed up in the quantum chemistry calculations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AtmoSpec is poised to revolutionize the study of VOCs in atmospheric chemistry by providing an accessible and automated method for calculating photoabsorption cross-sections. It empowers researchers to gain deeper insights into the impact of these compounds on our environment without the need for costly laboratory experiments, and in a timely fashion. Whether you are a seasoned scientist or a newcomer to the field, AtmoSpec is a valuable resource that can enhance your understanding of a molecule’s photochemical properties. Additionally, with the planned improvements, its efficiency is set to increase dramatically resulting in wider applicability to more complex molecules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information and to access AtmoSpec, visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ispg-group/aiidalab-ispg&quot;&gt;ATMOSPEC GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;t60&quot;&gt;Other Blog posts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;side-nav&quot;&gt;

  

    
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/nuclear-ensemble-approach&quot;&gt;Photochemistry &amp;middot; &lt;strong&gt;The Nuclear Ensemble Approach&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/what-is-atmospec&quot;&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry &amp;middot; &lt;strong&gt;AtmoSpec: A Revolutionary Tool for Atmospheric Chemists&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/predicting-solubility&quot;&gt;Computational Chemistry &amp;middot; &lt;strong&gt;A Machine learning approach to the prediction of solubility&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    
      &lt;li class=&quot;text-right&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/archive/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More ›&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;


  
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/what-is-atmospec</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A Machine learning approach to the prediction of solubility</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/blog/predicting-solubility</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In the realms of pharmaceuticals and agrochemicals, solubility is a cornerstone of efficacy and safety. For pharmaceuticals, solubility determines how well a drug can dissolve in bodily fluids, impacting its bioavailability and therapeutic effectiveness. Poor solubility can lead to inadequate drug absorption, reduced efficacy, and potential toxicity due to crystallization within the body1. In agrochemicals, solubility affects the environmental behavior and toxicity of compounds, influencing their effectiveness and safety in agricultural applications1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why Solubility Matters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pharmaceuticals: High solubility ensures that drugs can be absorbed efficiently into the bloodstream, enhancing their therapeutic impact. It also mitigates risks associated with poorly soluble drugs, such as crystallization and toxicity1.
Agrochemicals: Solubility influences how chemicals interact with the environment, affecting their distribution, effectiveness, and potential environmental impact1.
Challenges in Solubility Prediction: Traditional methods for determining solubility, such as turbidimetric and potentiometric techniques, are time-consuming and resource-intensive1. High-throughput screening methods have improved efficiency but still face limitations in terms of cost and scalability1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning to the Rescue: Machine learning (ML) offers a transformative approach to predicting solubility. By leveraging vast datasets and advanced algorithms, ML models can predict solubility with high accuracy, reducing the need for extensive experimental testing1. Graph Convolutional Networks (GCNs), in particular, have shown promise in modeling molecular structures and predicting properties like solubility1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benefits of ML in Solubility Prediction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Efficiency: ML models can rapidly screen large libraries of compounds, identifying promising candidates without the need for exhaustive experimental testing1.
Accuracy: Advanced ML algorithms can capture complex relationships between molecular structures and solubility, providing reliable predictions1.
Resource Optimization: By reducing the reliance on experimental methods, ML helps conserve valuable resources and accelerates the development process1.
In conclusion, the integration of machine learning into solubility prediction represents a significant advancement for both the pharmaceutical and agrochemical industries. It not only enhances the efficiency and accuracy of solubility assessments but also supports the development of safer and more effective compounds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/predicting-solubility</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Representative sampling in the Nuclear Ensemble Approach - full report</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/rep-sampling-for-nea/thesis-report/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;embed src=&quot;/assets/thesis_report.pdf&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; type=&quot;application/pdf&quot; /&gt;

</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/rep-sampling-for-nea/thesis-report/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Biscuit dunking analysis report</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/biscuit-dunking-analysis/biscuit-report/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;embed src=&quot;/assets/biscuit_report.pdf&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; type=&quot;application/pdf&quot; /&gt;

</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/biscuit-dunking-analysis/biscuit-report/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Atmospec data visualization module report</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/atmospec-data-visualization-module/atmospec-report/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;embed src=&quot;/assets/atmospec_report.pdf&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; type=&quot;application/pdf&quot; /&gt;

</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/atmospec-data-visualization-module/atmospec-report/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>ATLAS data processing report</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/cloud-paradigm-atlas-data-processing/atlas-report/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;embed src=&quot;/assets/atlas_report.pdf&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; type=&quot;application/pdf&quot; /&gt;

</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/cloud-paradigm-atlas-data-processing/atlas-report/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Web Building Homepage</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/guides/web-building/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 medium-push-8 columns&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;panel radius&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p id=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#coming-soon&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-coming-soon&quot;&gt;Coming Soon!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- /.medium-4.columns --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;medium-8 medium-pull-4 columns&quot;&gt;

    &lt;h2 id=&quot;coming-soon&quot;&gt;Coming Soon!&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/guides/web-building/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Guides Archive</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/guides/toc/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;div id=&quot;guides-index&quot; class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;small-12 columns t30&quot;&gt;
		&lt;h1&gt;Guides Archive&lt;/h1&gt;
		&lt;p class=&quot;teaser&quot;&gt;Explore all the guides and tutorials available in the Guides section.&lt;/p&gt;

		&lt;dl class=&quot;accordion&quot; data-accordion=&quot;&quot;&gt;
			

			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
					&lt;dd class=&quot;accordion-navigation&quot;&gt;
						&lt;a href=&quot;#panel1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;iconfont&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; HTML and CSS › &lt;strong&gt;Web Building Homepage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
						&lt;div id=&quot;panel1&quot; class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
							web design and implementation... 
							&lt;a href=&quot;/guides/web-building/&quot; title=&quot;Read Web Building Homepage&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read More&amp;nbsp;›&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/dd&gt;
					
				
			
				
					&lt;dd class=&quot;accordion-navigation&quot;&gt;
						&lt;a href=&quot;#panel2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;iconfont&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Guides Archive&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
						&lt;div id=&quot;panel2&quot; class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
							Explore all the guides and tutorials available in the Guides section.
							&lt;a href=&quot;/guides/toc/&quot; title=&quot;Read Guides Archive&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read More&amp;nbsp;›&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/dd&gt;
					
				
			
				
					&lt;dd class=&quot;accordion-navigation&quot;&gt;
						&lt;a href=&quot;#panel3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;iconfont&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Python › &lt;strong&gt;Python Homepage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
						&lt;div id=&quot;panel3&quot; class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
							Python ... 
							&lt;a href=&quot;/guides/python/&quot; title=&quot;Read Python Homepage&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read More&amp;nbsp;›&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/dd&gt;
					
				
			
				
					&lt;dd class=&quot;accordion-navigation&quot;&gt;
						&lt;a href=&quot;#panel4&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;iconfont&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Other Guides › &lt;strong&gt;Other Homepage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
						&lt;div id=&quot;panel4&quot; class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
							Other Guides... 
							&lt;a href=&quot;/guides/other/&quot; title=&quot;Read Other Homepage&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read More&amp;nbsp;›&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/dd&gt;
					
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			

			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
					&lt;dd class=&quot;accordion-navigation&quot;&gt;
						&lt;a href=&quot;#panel5&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;iconfont&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Learn with me!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
						&lt;div id=&quot;panel5&quot; class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
							Topics include Python coding and packages, as well as Jekyll, HTML and SCSS
							&lt;a href=&quot;/guides/&quot; title=&quot;Read Learn with me!&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read More&amp;nbsp;›&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/dd&gt;
					
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
				
			
		&lt;/dl&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- /.small-12.columns --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;!-- /.row --&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/guides/toc/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Python Homepage</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/guides/python/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 medium-push-8 columns&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;panel radius&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p id=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#coming-soon&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-coming-soon&quot;&gt;Coming Soon!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- /.medium-4.columns --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;medium-8 medium-pull-4 columns&quot;&gt;

    &lt;h2 id=&quot;coming-soon&quot;&gt;Coming Soon!&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/guides/python/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
